you got to give me about five seconds to
get the fight-or-flight response to
process through my body before I can be
effective here so it turns out that I do
a pretty good job of being in a solvent
and being a catalyst so my intent is in
fact to do that for this group to the
extent that I can and an answer to
something you brought up which is very
important my commitment is to interact
in good faith to the best so that I
don't do that to my ability so that's
the front end so starting off the Tyler
was I don't know something about
complexity probably the better title be
like is up and stuff the
notion is that we've got a toolkit it's
a legacy toolkit that toolkit sucks it's
broken it doesn't work very well we have
to free ourselves of that toolkit
because intuitively whenever we come
across a problem we're going to reach
into it and try to solve the problem
with that toolkit so we've got to figure
out how to break our mind of that and
then reconstitute a new toolkit I'm very
interested to find out what it looks
like
so think different think very different
now we've done this before fortunately
this is not the first time we've been to
this rodeo so I'll take the example of
journalism this is legacy journalism now
unfortunately when you go to certain
circumstances back in the 2000 timeframe
and everybody talked about
reconstituting journalism they thought
that's what reconstituting doodles would
look like alright because you take your
toolkit you turn the crank on journalism
I think the New York Times I put it on
my computer yeah but of course in fact
we know that that's actually what
journalism looks like in the 21st
century you boil it down to the base
functions journalism is the sourcing the
qualification and the dissemination of
information into a network that's a
journalism is as a fundamental function
is that the same category as science
although of course different many ways
and then you begin to imagine using your
new toolkit how do you create
instruments to affect that particular
function so that's the basic idea of
what we have to do in general with
journalism being a base great case is
point okay so what is governance if we
take that particular mode right what are
the core functions of this idea of
governance and it's trying to solve a
couple of basic fundamental problems
that seem to emerge in any kind of
coordination Network the coordination
problem the prisoner's dilemma collected
decision-making the tragedy the Commons
conflict management it may be bigger or
smaller that's the basic ideas it's some
bucket of things that look like this
now the legacy toolkit has a pretty
solid way of trying to solve these
problems to Leviathan and what we
currently live in you might call the
peak predator of Leviathan space they've
been evolving against each other
competing a wide variety of different
ways
pending unfortunately on occasion to
figure out how to systematically kill
each other and almost all of our toolkit
is some modulation on Leviathan space
call it sovereignty at the top
percolating down hierarchy bureaucracy
commodification normalization etc Center
ok then we have to do is we have to do
something different so these are the
design constraints on any future
instruments in the 21st century this is
by no means comprehensive that's
probably wrong with the idea to try to
start gesturing in the right direction
some key ideas decentralization if
you're building something which requires
a transcendent institution to be able to
solve those governance problems you're
probably doing something wrong you have
to focus first and foremost in building
something which is decentralized and
uses imminent interlocutory feedback
loops to enable the emergence of
structure when an if necessary
probably results using different
different kinds of currencies and
specifically some variation on the kinds
of reputation currencies that humans
primates sensors are tuned to be able to
react to effectively of course as long
as you're building a lot of people we
may be building about other kinds of
objects that have no in that case
different receivers a second there's a
phrase architectures politics can you
take that actually seriously a lot of
the things that we currently do in
institutional form we will actually need
to do in software form so lots of good
reasons software is scalable software is
portable software is transparent by
design and I mean this very seriously if
you're designing something think first
and foremost how can I design this as
software next fluid and continuous
versus siloed
we have this weird problem that people
right now live in silos you're a
bureaucrat you are at the IFT f you are
etc etc the future is going to be fluid
to figure out how you build something
that people can partially attract to
something and participate in it and then
jump out of it in different ways
empowered individuals if you're building
a machine that works in spite of
incompetent individuals your
because you'll get incompetent
individuals scalable across the system
it has to be fault tolerant to
incompetent individuals but
fundamentally oriented towards building
capable individuals at the edge in all
circumstances ad hoc and fine grained
polymorphic solving problems with ad hoc
solutions building out architectures as
necessary and then bringing them down
and being receptive to the fact that you
could have a very high degree of firing
precision and discernment to build them
effectively right not grosgrain not
coarse-grained but being able to be very
nuanced and last transparent by design
right not just transparent and intention
but designed effectively and
intelligently to be able to maintain
transparency in spite of a wide variety
of different feedback to attend to cogs
to not be transparent based on the way
humans tend to interact